A Guide to the Papers of Paul T. David 1944-1994
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Paul T. David 1944-1994
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12793
Ca. 100 items (3 Hollinger boxes, 1 linear foot).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the University of Virginia Library by Paul T. David in 1961.
Biographical/Historical Information
Economist, government official, author, University of Virginia professor from 1960-1977 (former chairman of the Dept. of Political Science and Woodrow Wilson Dept. of Foreign Affairs; elected Professor Emeritus of Government and Foreign Affairs 1977 April).
Scope and Content
This set of papers from UVA political science professor Paul T. David consists of ca. 100 items (3 Hollinger boxes, 1 linear foot) and includes reports and correspondence by and between David and others on the development of commercial aviation in the post-World War II period. There is a set of bound volumes of transcripts of an oral interview of David conducted in 1990-1992. There is correspondence between David and Richard Niehoff concerning a biography of noted educational statesman Floyd W. Reeves and a copy of the draft biography.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by topic (aviation, oral history transcripts, and Reeves biography). Aviation materials are arranged alphabetically by material type. Oral history transcripts are arranged chronologically. The Reeves materials are divided into correspondence and manuscript.
Contents List
- Aviation-Correspondence with Michael Milde 1993-1994 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Aviation-Correspondence with L. Welch Pogue 1992-1994 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Aviation-Reports 1993 (Box-folder 1:3)
  The International Civil Aviation Conference and Its Sequel The Anglo-American Bermuda Air Transport Agreements and International Civil Aviation Conference, Chicago, 1944: Some Issues Decided, and Events Occurring There; The 1946 Bermuda air Transport Agreement by L. Welch Pogue and John Marshall Pogue.
- Aviation-Reports 1944 (Box-folder 1:4)
  Report to the Civil Aeronautics Board on the Chicago International Aviation Conference and Development of the Convention of International Civil Aviation by Virginia C. Little
- Aviation-Report 1994 (Box-folder 1:5)
  A Review of the Work at the Chicago Conference (from a Secretariat Point of View) by Paul T. David
- Oral History - Guide to "The Oral History of Dr. Paul T. David" 1992 (Box-folder 1:6)
- Oral History 1990 Nov. 14 (Box-folder 1:7)
  American Political Science Association Oral History Project, The University of Kentucky Library, Paul David Interviewee, Laurin Henry Interviewer (in binder)
- Oral History 1990 Nov. 20 (Box-folder 1:8)
- Oral History 1990 Nov. 29 (Box-folder 1:9)
- Oral History 1990 Dec. 6 (Box-folder 1:10)
- Oral History 1991 Nov. 15 (Box-folder 2:1)
- Oral History 1991 Nov. 22 (Box-folder 2:2)
- Oral History 1991 Dec. 3 (Box-folder 2:3)
- Oral History 1992 Feb. 25 (Box-folder 2:4)
- Oral History 1992 Feb. 27 (Box-folder 2:5)
- Oral History 1992 Mar. 4 (Box-folder 2:6)
- Oral History 1992 Mar. 6 (Box-folder 2:7)
- Oral History 1992 Mar. 19 (Box-folder 2:8)
- Oral History 1992 Mar. 19 (Box-folder 2:9)
- Oral History 1992 Mar. 31 (Box-folder 3:1)
- Oral History 1992 Apr. 8 (Box-folder 3:2)
- Oral History 1992 Apr. 15 (Box-folder 3:3)
- Reeves Manuscript 1980-1993 (Box-folder 3:4)
  Correspondence with Richard (Dick) Niehoff Concerning Book about Floyd Reeves and Other Topics
- Reeves Manuscript - Manuscript of Floyd W. Reeves by Richard O. Niehoff (1 of 3 folders) ca. 1990 (Box-folder 4:5)
- Reeves Manuscript - Manuscript of Floyd W. Reeves by Richard O. Niehoff (2 of 3 folders) ca. 1990 (Box-folder 4:6)
- Reeves Manuscript - Manuscript of Floyd W. Reeves by Richard O. Niehoff (3 of 3 folders) ca. 1990 (Box-folder 4:7)